<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Padlock Newsletter</title>
    <link>https://padlock.io/news/</link>
    <description>Recent news about Padlock and Padlock Cloud</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://padlock.io/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Padlock v1.0 Released</title>
      <link>https://padlock.io/news/v1.0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://padlock.io/news/v1.0-released/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re pleased to announce that Padlock v1.0 has been released! This is the biggest release yet, and apart from the usual bug fixes and polish we have a couple of neat additions for you (see below)! Most the changes, though, have been &amp;ldquo;under the hood&amp;rdquo; and even though they are not directly visible to most users they will bring great improvements in stability, reliability and security. Security, of course, has always been our main priority when building Padlock and we&amp;rsquo;re happy to tell you that we have been working with the Open Technology Fund and the security experts at cure53 to identify and eliminate possible vulnerabilities and further strengthen the security of the app!</description>
      <content:encoded>

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re pleased to announce that &lt;strong&gt;Padlock v1.0 has been released&lt;/strong&gt;! This is the
biggest release yet, and apart from the usual bug fixes and polish we have a
couple of neat additions for you (see below)! Most the changes, though, have
been &amp;ldquo;under the hood&amp;rdquo; and even though they are not directly visible to most
users they will bring great improvements in stability, reliability and
security. Security, of course, has always been our main priority when building
Padlock and we&amp;rsquo;re happy to tell you that we have been working with the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.opentech.fund/&#34;&gt;Open Technology Fund&lt;/a&gt; and the security experts at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cure53.de/&#34;&gt;cure53&lt;/a&gt; to identify and eliminate possible vulnerabilities
and further strengthen the security of the app! We&amp;rsquo;ll be releasing the full
report soon so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;note&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important:&lt;/strong&gt; Along with this release, we&amp;rsquo;re also rolling out a major update
to the Padlock Cloud service. As a result, &lt;strong&gt;older version of the Padlock
app will no longer work with Padlock Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;! See our
&lt;a href=&#34;https://padlock.io/news/pc-update-required/&#34;&gt;announcement&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;auto-lock&#34;&gt;Auto Lock&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;float right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://padlock.io/img/auto-lock.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Auto Lock&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Previously the iOS and Android versions of the app would lock instantly the
moment you put the app in the background.  This proved to be a major
inconvenience for many users since you had to re-enter your master password
every time you switched apps in order to copy &amp;amp; paste user names and
passwords into webpages or other applications. On the other hand, the desktop
app did not have any form of auto-locking at all. With the latest release, both
mobile and desktop apps now automatically detect if they haven&amp;rsquo;t received any
input from the user in a while and &lt;strong&gt;will automatically lock after a
configurable period of inactivity&lt;/strong&gt;. This not only means that your data will be
safe in case you forget to close the app on your computer or phone - copying
and pasting will now also be a lot easier since the app will no longer lock
instantly the moment you switch to another app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;improved-padlock-cloud-pairing-process&#34;&gt;Improved Padlock Cloud Pairing Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We put a lot of working into making pairing your devices with Padlock
Cloud easier and more intuitive. At the same time, we added some features to
make the process more secure and give you more control over your data.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;float left&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://padlock.io/img/pc-restore.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Restore From Padlock Cloud&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Among other things, you can now restore your Account directly from Padlock
Cloud when starting the app on a new device!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-padlock-cloud-server&#34;&gt;Custom Padlock Cloud Server&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the power users among you &lt;strong&gt;Padlock now supports pairing with your own,
custom Padlock Cloud server&lt;/strong&gt;! Openness and transparency have always been a major
part of our philosophy and even though we make sure that your data never leaves
your devices unencrypted, we understand if some people don&amp;rsquo;t want to upload
their data to a server they don&amp;rsquo;t control. If you want to learn more about how
you can spin up your own Padlock Cloud instance, head over to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/maklesoft/padlock-cloud&#34;&gt;Padlock Cloud on Github&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you like the new version! If you have any feedback, questions or
concerns, feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@padlock.io&#34;&gt;shoot us an email&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update to v1.0 to Keep Using Padlock Cloud!</title>
      <link>https://padlock.io/news/pc-update-required/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://padlock.io/news/pc-update-required/</guid>
      <description>Along with the release of Padlock v1.0 we are also rolling out a major update to the Padlock Cloud service. Unfortunately, this means that Padlock Cloud clients of version 0.12 or earlier will not be able to access Padlock Cloud anymore. When trying to synchronize data or pair new devices, the app will show a generic error message. In addition, users will receive an email reminding them to update to the latest version of Padlock.</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Along with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://padlock.io/news/v1.0-released/&#34;&gt;release of Padlock v1.0&lt;/a&gt; we
are also rolling out a major update to the Padlock Cloud service.
Unfortunately, this means that &lt;strong&gt;Padlock Cloud clients of version 0.12 or
earlier will not be able to access Padlock Cloud anymore&lt;/strong&gt;.  When trying to
synchronize data or pair new devices, the app will show a generic error
message.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;float right&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://padlock.io/img/screen-error.png&#34; alt=&#34;Generic Error Message&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In addition, users will receive an email reminding them to update to the latest
version of Padlock. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, your data is still there! In order to keep
using Padlock Cloud, simply &lt;strong&gt;update the app to v1.0 or greater&lt;/strong&gt;. Note that
after updating the app, you will also have to pair your device again. To do
this, simply go to &lt;strong&gt;Settings &amp;gt; Padlock Cloud&lt;/strong&gt; and select &lt;strong&gt;Connect&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We apologize for any inconvenience this might cause. If you have any questions
or concerns, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:support@padlock.io&#34;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
